<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jishnu Nair</title>
    <link>https://jishnunair.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jishnu Nair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:57:20 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jishnunair.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Privacy?</title>
      <link>https://jishnunair.net/posts/why-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 14:57:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jishnunair.net/posts/why-privacy/</guid>
      
        <description>The Beginning Over the past two years, I have been on a quest to reclaim my digital privacy (as much as possible).
So how did this journey start? I think it all started with Linux, or GNU/Linux. My search for what GNU is led me to beginnings of the Free Software movement, Richard Stallman, and the four essential freedoms. All this led me to the question, &amp;ldquo;How much control do I have over my digital life?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is Water</title>
      <link>https://jishnunair.net/posts/this-is-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 22:05:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jishnunair.net/posts/this-is-water/</guid>
      
        <description>This is a commencement speech delivered by David Foster Wallace to the graduates of a liberal arts course. The essence of this talk is the value of education, which is about &amp;ldquo;simple awareness – awareness of what is so real and essential, so hidden in plain sight all around us, that we have to keep reminding ourselves over and over: This is water.&amp;quot;
The phrase &amp;ldquo;This is water&amp;rdquo; refers to the story he mentions at the beginning of the speech, which I quote here:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Woods</title>
      <link>https://jishnunair.net/posts/a-walk-in-the-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 20:02:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jishnunair.net/posts/a-walk-in-the-woods/</guid>
      
        <description>The Appalachian Trail is one of the longest hiking trails in the world, extending about 3,500 km across 14 states in the United States. This book follows Bill Bryson&amp;rsquo;s experiences as he hikes the trail with his friend. I have currently read the first part of this book, with Bill and his friend realizing that they will never be able to hike the entire trail, but still deciding to hike as much as they can by skipping certain parts of the stretch.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jishnunair.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jishnunair.net/about/</guid>
      
        <description>Who am I? I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. Nobody really knows who they are.
Society in general chooses profession or academic position to define people. &amp;ldquo;I am X, and I do this. I study this. That is the entirety of who I am.&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m just gonna go with &amp;ldquo;I do not know. But you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to find out!&amp;rdquo;
What do I do? Again I do not want to start with my profession.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jishnunair.net/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jishnunair.net/contact/</guid>
      
        <description>I can be contacted on email.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in sending an encrypted mail, here&amp;rsquo;s my public key</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>